<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<concept id="DLAD_53_9013">
   <title outputclass="Heading 3"> 
      <ph props="autonumber">53.9013</ph> Simplified acquisition procedures.</title><conbody>
   <p id="Gltewj">(a) <i>Simplified Acquisition Award Documentation (SAAD).</i> </p>
   <p>Contracting officers at DLA Aviation, DLA Land and Maritime, and DLA Troop Support shall use the following format as prescribed in <xref href="13.106-3.dita#DLAD_13_106-3" xtrc="13.106-3" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">13.106-3 Award and documentation.</xref> (b), <xref href="13.501.dita#DLAD_13_501" xtrc="13.501" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">13.501 Special documentation requirements.</xref>(b) (3), and <xref href="15.406-1.dita#DLAD_15_406-1/fdfdb1" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">15.406-1 Prenegotiation objectives.</xref>. (Mark “FOR OFFICIAL USE ONLY”, when applicable, at the bottom of the outside of the front cover (if there is one), the title page, the first page, and the outside of the back cover (if there is one) pursuant to DOD Manual 5200.1, Vol 4, Enclosure 3, 2.c.(3)(b).) <i>This Simplified Acquisition Award Documentation (SAAD) format is for illustration purposes only. It mirrors the fillable version in the contract writing system.</i> <p id="blZQbE" outputclass="Ctr normal"> <b>Simplified Acquisition Award Documentation (SAAD)</b> </p> <p id="PrVCVX" outputclass="Normal">The SAAD documents Best Value, Price Reasonableness, and Responsibility determinations for this procurement.</p> <p id="KaoQfk" outputclass="Ctr normal"> <b> <u>Particulars Regarding This Procurement:</u> </b> </p> <p id="ZlyUYP" outputclass="Normal">Buyer:</p> <p id="pgyRct" outputclass="Normal">PR#:</p> <p id="wobcds" outputclass="Normal">NSN (if applicable):</p> <p id="LbfSwk" outputclass="Normal">Item/Requirement Description:</p> <p id="gkluyp" outputclass="Normal">Awardee CAGE Code:</p> <p id="ChOVlt" outputclass="Normal">Check all that apply and insert narrative when required:</p> <p id="kubnvN" outputclass="Normal">☐ Procurement is a First Time Buy</p> <p id="qClJSR" outputclass="Normal">☐ Commercial</p> <p id="hzoLbr" outputclass="Normal">☐ For non-competitive actions over $1M Contract Business Analysis Repository (CBAR) was checked IAW DLAD <xref href="15.404-1.dita#DLAD_15_404-1" xtrc="15.404-1" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">15.404-1 Proposal analysis techniques.</xref>(a)(5)(S-90)</p> <p id="pqXyVO" outputclass="Normal">☐ Fast Pay (FAR 13.402(a)-(f))</p> <p id="SmwHNQ" outputclass="Normal">☐ Special Emergency Procurement Authority (SEPA) Acquisition (FAR 18.001)<p>☐ Simplified Indefinite-Delivery Contract (SIDC). The contracting officer established a guaranteed minimum (GM) quantity or GM dollar value for the period of performance of the basic SIDC, recorded an obligation in the amount of the GM purchase requirement ($________) at time of award, and placed the EBS screen shot documenting the obligation in the contract file IAW DLAD 13.390(a)(2)(i).</p> </p> <p id="qcMGMA" outputclass="Normal"> <b> <u>Best Value Tradeoff Determination:</u> </b> <b>Required when awarding to other than the lowest price/highest SPRS rating (or to other than the lowest price/highest scored when using FAR 13.5 or when other evaluation factors apply).</b> </p> <p id="xtfcjO" outputclass="Normal">☐ Based on the evaluation factors stated within the solicitation, the proposed awardee’s quote is the best value for the Government as set forth in the narrative below.</p> <p id="XslZGu" outputclass="Normal"> <b>Narrative:</b> </p> <p id="77auehgc" outputclass="Normal">CUI Designation Indicator </p> <p id="l9wvaflx" outputclass="Normal">Controlled by: [Name of Procuring Organization]<p>Controlled by: [Name of Office or Branch]</p> <p>CUI Category: PROCURE (General Procurement)</p> <p>Distribution/Dissemination Control: FED ONLY</p> <p>POC: [Phone or email address]</p> </p> <p id="rLysAq" outputclass="Normal"> <b> <u>Price Reasonableness Determination</u> </b> </p> <p id="IrbUQx" outputclass="Normal"> <b>Limitation on Price Increases (DFARS 217.7505/DLAD</b> <xref href="17.7505.dita#DLAD_17_7505" xtrc="17.7505" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">17.7505 Limitations on price increases.</xref> <b>):</b> </p> <p id="kgicmq" outputclass="Normal">For Micro-Purchases:</p> <p id="PNgFHK" outputclass="List2">☐ Unit Price has not increased 51% or more within the past 12 months.</p> <p id="iacrMr" outputclass="List2">☐ Unit Price has increased 51% or more within the past 12 months. Contracting officer has evaluated price and will notify HCA (or HCA’s designee) prior to award.</p> <p id="GPBxxl" outputclass="List2">For actions above the micro-purchase threshold documented using simplified acquisition procedures:</p> <p id="pozrce" outputclass="List2">☐ Unit Price has not increased 25% or more within the past 12 months.</p> <p id="jdlgCA" outputclass="List2">☐ Unit Price has increased 25% or more within the past 12 months. Contracting officer has evaluated price and will notify HCA (or HCA’s designee) prior to award.</p> <p id="gubfOp" outputclass="Normal"> <b>Price Reasonableness Code (PRC):</b> </p> <p id="WisOPT" outputclass="Normal"/> <p id="KuInlk" outputclass="Normal"> <b>Basis for Award- <u>FAR</u> <u>13.106-3(a), DLAD 13.106-3(a) &amp; DLAD</u> </b> <xref href="15.406-3.dita#DLAD_15_406-3" xtrc="15.406-3" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">15.406-3 Documenting the negotiation.</xref> <xref href="15.406-3.dita#DLAD_15_406-3/p_P15_406_3_a" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"> <u>(a)(11)</u>15.406-3 Documenting the negotiation.</xref> <b> <u>:</u> </b> </p> <p id="yaBlLX" outputclass="Normal">Price is Fair and Reasonable in accordance with (<b>check blocks below as applicable AND complete Narrative at end of this section);</b> </p> <p id="UFrgej" outputclass="Normal">☐ Adequate Price Competition – Manufacturer Competition</p> <p id="MCWSeZ" outputclass="Normal">☐ Adequate Price Competition – Among Providers of Services</p> <p id="xiRdvU" outputclass="Normal">☐ Adequate Price Competition – Dealer Competition (only use below SAT). Offered prices are independent, and otherwise successful offeror’s price is not unreasonable. <b>Provide documentation in Narrative block.</b> </p> <p id="fEsdIv" outputclass="Normal">☐ No Competition (single quote or noncompetitive price range).</p> <p id="tMvJQk" outputclass="Normal">Select one of the following:</p> <p id="fWoEYQ" outputclass="List2">☐ Market Research <b>(describe in Narrative block; or attach and reference in Narrative block)</b> </p> <p id="qQTBXW" outputclass="List2">☐ Item price set by law or regulation</p> <p id="ZGUCOc" outputclass="List2">☐ Independent Government Estimate (IGE). Attach the IGE, if Contracting Officer determines IGE required adjustment, address in Narrative block.</p> <p id="zlGtKo" outputclass="List2">☐ Comparison of the proposed price to prices found reasonable on previous purchases: Provide analysis in Narrative block.</p> <p id="oEsbvu" outputclass="List1">☐ Same Item: <ph outputclass="List3">☐ Similar Item (NSN or Item Description):</ph> </p> <p id="Qqajwp" outputclass="Normal">Contract(s):</p> <p id="lxbjlk" outputclass="List2">Unit Price(s):</p> <p id="FqYSUF" outputclass="List2">Quantity:</p> <p id="WsAmFP" outputclass="List2">PRC applicable previous purchase:</p> <p id="WELWFI" outputclass="List2">Prior award determined fair and reasonable based on:</p> <p id="cbanre" outputclass="List2">☐ Current price list, catalog, or advertised unit price: <b>Describe in Narrative block.</b> </p> <p id="ubbgtz" outputclass="List2">☐ Contracting officer’s knowledge of the item. <b>Describe in Narrative block.</b> </p> <p id="buneQQ" outputclass="List2">☐ Any other reasonable basis (e.g., informal cost breakdown) <b>Describe in Narrative block.</b> </p> <p id="iJYmTs" outputclass="Normal">Price is other than Fair and Reasonable and proceeding after proper elevation IAW DLAD 15.405(d)(S-90) (check blocks below as applicable AND complete Narrative at end of this section);</p> <p id="MwKsKb" outputclass="Normal">☐ Price is <i>unfair</i> and <i>unreasonable</i>. <b>Complete Narrative block.</b> </p> <p id="bVVcOF" outputclass="Normal">☐ Price could <i>not</i> be determined fair and reasonable. <b>Complete Narrative block.</b> </p> <p id="CRodwK" outputclass="Normal"> <b>Narrative (Must address any price increase since last purchase along with any negotiations that were conducted. Attach or provide the location within the contract file for all supporting documentation):</b> </p> <p id="SuhONo" outputclass="Normal"/> <p id="itfVDM" outputclass="Normal"/> <p id="NMvyou" outputclass="Normal"/> <p id="nwgcwI" outputclass="Normal"> <b>Determination of Responsibility:</b> </p> <p id="FfxoaY" outputclass="Normal">Check all applicable blocks and complete Narrative when required:</p> <p id="CEKyFy" outputclass="Normal">☐ Confirmed whether contractor is on the Defense Contract Review List (DCRL) and followed applicable Treatment Codes.</p> <p id="srolXQ" outputclass="Normal">☐ Contracting officer checked SAM.gov (FAR 9.405(d)(4)). Awardee is not debarred, suspended, or proposed for suspension/debarment. Awardee is currently in SAM.</p> <p id="zxFnwb" outputclass="Normal">Date SAM Checked:____________________</p> <p id="vhACFT" outputclass="Normal">☐ For competitive solicitations for supplies using FAR part 13 simplified acquisition procedures, including acquisitions valued at less than or equal to $1 million under the authority at FAR subpart 13.5, contracting officer reviewed the Supplier Performance Risk System (SPRS) IAW DFARS 213.106-2(b)(i).</p> <p id="HzMZeX" outputclass="Normal"> <b>The contracting officer’s signature on the award document constitutes evidence that the contracting officer has considered the issues listed and described above and arrived at the findings, determinations, and conclusions also enumerated above for the above-identified procurement.</b> </p> <p id="428jiuqx">(b) <i>Market Research for Commerciality Determination Memorandum for Record (MRCDM).</i> </p> <p id="kXRnRn" outputclass="Normal">The contracting officer shall use the MRCDM format as prescribed in <xref href="13.501.dita#DLAD_13_501" xtrc="13.501)" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">13.501(b)(3)</xref> The contracting officer shall include a “Source Selection Information” legend when applicable pursuant to FAR 2.101 and 3.104. Procuring organizations may append the MRCDM to the acquisition plan, and the acquisition plan may refer to the MRCDM in sections regarding market research and sustainability. <i>This Market Research for Commerciality Determination Memorandum (MRCDM) format</i> <i>is for illustration purposes only. It mirrors the fillable version in the contract writing system.</i> </p> <p id="xvAmRG" outputclass="Ctr normal"> <b>MEMORANDUM FOR RECORD</b> </p> <p id="yhdjQd" outputclass="Normal">SUBJECT: Market Research for Commerciality Determination (MRCDM) (FAR 10.002, FAR 2.101, and FAR 13.5)</p> <p id="uvpNcY" outputclass="Ctr normal">(Mark “FOR OFFICIAL USE ONLY”, when applicable, at the bottom of the outside of the front cover (if there is one), the title page, the first page, and the outside of the back cover (if there is one) pursuant to DOD Manual 5200.1, Vol 4, Enclosure 3, 2.c.(3)(b).)</p> <p id="ckbPJF" outputclass="Normal">Market research has been conducted prior to solicitation:</p> <p id="JDVSgK" outputclass="Normal">Solicitation #: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert)</u> </i>NSN(s) (if applicable): <i> <u>(contracting officer insert)</u> </i> </p> <p id="ZpRkfn" outputclass="Normal">Item/Requirement Description: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert)</u> </i> </p> <p id="yUCdFw" outputclass="Normal">PR#: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert)</u> </i> </p> <p id="qqfDNm" outputclass="Normal"/> <p id="i7nkpra" outputclass="Normal">PART I</p> <p id="lsDeia" outputclass="Normal">In accordance with FAR 10.002(b) and FAR 2.101, Definitions, the cognizant functional element of the procuring organization has conducted a review of the item description(s) to determine if commercial items or non-developmental items are available to meet the government’s needs or could be modified to meet the government’s . The reviewer(s) considered the following:<i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="FHLjyY" outputclass="Normal">a. Whether items of a type are customarily available in the commercial marketplace; annotate evidence of actual sale, lease, or license to the general public, or evidence of items being offered for sale, lease or license to the general public: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="WlXNMT" outputclass="Normal">b. Whether items of a type are customarily available in the commercial marketplace with modifications; annotate evidence of actual sale, lease, or license to the general public and type of modification: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="HUWSBX" outputclass="Normal">c. Whether items are used exclusively for governmental purposes; annotate evidence that the items were (1) developed exclusively at private expense, and (2) sold competitively in substantial quantities to multiple state and local governments: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="vUvTgf" outputclass="Normal">d. Customary practices regarding customizing, modifying or tailoring of items to meet customers’ needs and associated costs; annotate evidence of customary availability of the modification in the commercial marketplace or the technical relationship between the modified items: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="yGEblG" outputclass="Normal">e. Customary practices, including warranty, buyer financing, discounts, contract type considering the nature and risk associated with the requirement, etc., under which commercial sales of the products or services are made: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="YIukDc" outputclass="Normal">f. The applicability of any laws and/or regulations unique to the item being acquired:<i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="prBYuM" outputclass="Normal">g. The availability of items that contain recovered materials and items that are energy efficient: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="ZVkFDd" outputclass="Normal">h. The distribution and support capabilities of potential suppliers, including alternative arrangements and cost estimates: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="aWALgR" outputclass="Normal">i. The size and status of potential sources: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="aEMHLo" outputclass="Normal">j. Services of a type offered and sold competitively in substantial quantities in the commercial marketplace based on established catalog or market prices for specific tasks performed or specific outcomes to be achieved and under standard commercial terms and conditions: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="ufZvDK" outputclass="Normal">k. Whether existing contract solutions (including Best-In-Class (BIC) can be used to satisfy the requirement (IAW with Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Memorandum M-17-29): <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="XVnaeL" outputclass="Normal"/> <p id="xq78gib" outputclass="Normal">PART II</p> <p id="zjEMyr" outputclass="Normal">Check one or more of the following, as applicable, to identify techniques the reviewer(s) used to conduct market research and determine commerciality:</p> <p id="uqqLoL" outputclass="Normal">a. ( ) Commercial-Off-the-Shelf Field is coded;</p> <p id="IjEetF" outputclass="Normal">b. ( ) If item has been coded in SAP as commercial but non-commercial practices are required (e.g., QCCs, packaging, etc.), the justification for the use of these practices has been entered in SAP in the internal comments field;</p> <p id="bQCoXJ" outputclass="Normal">c. ( ) Contacted knowledgeable individuals in government and industry regarding market capabilities to meet requirements;</p> <p id="iAiMrw" outputclass="Normal">d. ( ) Published formal requests for information in appropriate technical or scientific journals or business publications;</p> <p id="UsfIDl" outputclass="Normal">e. ( ) Queried the Government-wide database of contracts and other procurement instruments intended for use by multiple agencies available at https://www.fpds.gov and other government and commercial databases that provide information relevant to agency acquisitions;</p> <p id="gKEqGa" outputclass="Normal">f. ( ) Participated in interactive, on-line communication among industry, acquisition personnel, and customers;</p> <p id="BHCnsE" outputclass="Normal">g. ( ) Obtained source lists of similar items from other contracting activities, agencies, trade associations, or sources;</p> <p id="WimGaf" outputclass="Normal">h. ( ) Reviewed the results of recent market research undertaken to meet similar or identical requirements;</p> <p id="HAyLtb" outputclass="Normal">I. ( ) Reviewed catalogs and other available product literature published, or [provided] on-line, by manufacturers, distributors, and dealers;</p> <p id="hpDQZF" outputclass="Normal">j. ( ) Conducted interchange meetings or held presolicitation conferences to involve potential offerors;</p> <p id="GMtrwQ" outputclass="Normal">k. ( ) Queried the Central Contractor Registration (CCR) via the System for Award Management (SAM) for small business sources, as applicable. (See FAR/DFARS Part 4 for information on SAM).</p> <p id="Uonwwd" outputclass="Normal">l. ( ) Other <i> <u>(</u> </i> <i> <u>contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="wxQXcR">Provide supporting documentation (to include a review of the Material Master in SAP for applicable items) for any of the blocks above in c. through l. that have been checked in this part of the form. Check the following block(s), as applicable:</p> <p id="jvDcTY">( ) Documentation is attached</p> <p id="sQIVID" outputclass="Normal">( ) Documentation is located in Records Management file/folder: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="SxfuFD" outputclass="Normal"/> <p id="jp2skdmn" outputclass="Normal">SUMMARY OF MARKET RESEARCH:</p> <p id="wyXJin" outputclass="Normal">Contacted product specialist or other technical representative on: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="DOzrpf" outputclass="Normal">OR</p> <p id="oKGmYq" outputclass="Normal">Product specialist/technical representative provided market research with the requirement on:</p> <p id="igLqpZ" outputclass="Normal"> <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="teFSyC" outputclass="Normal">Name of Product Specialist/Technical Representative: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="FfPiIF" outputclass="Normal">Date: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="yAUJvU" outputclass="Normal">Product specialist/technical representative provided concurrence:</p> <p id="TlspTl" outputclass="Normal">() Yes. If “Yes,” has the Material Master been updated: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="RQcpMw" outputclass="Normal">() No. If “No,” state reason for nonconcurrence and how resolved: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="BXvjhZ"/> <p id="nqqruo9k">Part III</p> <p id="KFBLbn">Check one of the following to indicate the type of contract:</p> <p id="nskbAT">() Firm Fixed Price (FFP)</p> <p id="QjfMGh">() Fixed Price with Economic Price Adjustment (FP w/EPA)</p> <p id="NITDoU">NOTE: For acquisitions of commercial items, the contracting officer may only award FFP or FP w/EPA type contracts, with limited exceptions (see FAR 12.207). If the contracting officer determines the requirement is not commercial, document the contract type selection in the acquisition plan.</p> <p id="nhNoRA"/> <p id="jnpyyyrb">Part IV</p> <p id="JqIySK">Check one of the following to indicate if consolidation or bundling applies:</p> <p id="WOMyJN">() Consolidation (see attached report/determination)</p> <p id="KxUYdN">() Bundling (see attached report/determination)</p> <p id="mtwzFK" outputclass="Normal">CONCLUSION:</p> <p id="JprUBk" outputclass="Normal">Based on the market research conducted, item(s) to be solicited against subject solicitation have been determined to be (check one of the following):</p> <p id="CFkLfR" outputclass="Normal">() Commercial</p> <p id="puCAkm" outputclass="Normal">() Noncommercial</p> <p id="xnYmQR" outputclass="Normal"/> <p id="fk2m9ghw" outputclass="Normal">APPROVALS:</p> <p id="JvxyXo" outputclass="Normal">Name of Contracting Officer: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="eeNujn" outputclass="Normal">Signature: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert signature)</u> </i> </p> <p id="PwKhTF" outputclass="Normal">Date: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert date)</u> </i> </p> <p id="RlGWtP" outputclass="Normal">Name of Approving Official (One Level Above Contracting Officer): <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="SInnGe" outputclass="Normal">Title: <i> <u>(contracting officer insert response)</u> </i> </p> <p id="bHLXYP" outputclass="Normal">Signature: <i> <u>(approving official insert signature)</u> </i> </p> <p id="KjjvVd" outputclass="Normal">Date: <i> <u>(approving official insert date)</u> </i> </p> <p id="qypsXn" outputclass="Normal">(Applies when contracting officer based commercial item determination on subsections (1)(ii), (3), (4), or (6) of the “commercial item” definition at FAR 2.101.)</p> <p outputclass="List1">(c) Alternate Simplified Acquisition Award Documentation (SAAD). Contracting officers at DLA Distribution, DLA Disposition Services, DLA Contracting Services Office, DLA Strategic Materials, and DLA Energy shall use the <xref href="https://dlamil.dps.mil/teams/C12/N608/FormTemplates/SAAD%20(Alternate)%2010-27-21.pdf" format="html" scope="external">SAAD (Alternate) 10-27-21.pdf</xref> (<xref href="https://dlamil.dps.mil/teams/C12/N608/FormTemplates/SAAD%20(Alternate)%2010-27-21.pdf" format="html" scope="external">https://dlamil.dps.mil/teams/C12/N608/FormTemplates/SAAD%20(Alternate)%2010-27-21.pdf</xref>) as prescribed in <xref href="13.106-3.dita" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"/>(b), <xref href="13.501.dita" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"/>(b)(3), and <xref href="15.406-1.dita" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"/>(b)(1). DLA Distribution maintains the Alternate SAAD online. The contracting officer must sign the format. </p> </p></conbody></concept>
